all: Behold!
全体：看哪！
We are the Greek chorus.
我们是希腊合唱团。
We narrate this epic tale
我们讲述这个史诗般的故事
of stupidity.
的愚蠢。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
[clear throats]
[清嗓子]
Behold Neptune,
看海王星，
god of the sea,
海神，
with his mighty trident,
带着他强大的三叉戟，
a weapon so powerful
如此强大的武器
nothing is beyond
its user's reach.
没有什么是超越的
它的用户范围。
Behold the Kraken.
看海妖。
- [snarling]
- [咆哮]
all: Gross monster.
全体：恶心的怪物。
- [snarling]
- [咆哮]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [grunting]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
all: Behold Neptune triumphant.
所有人：看海王星胜利了。
What an awesome dude.
多么棒的家伙啊。
Behold this idiot
and beware,
看看这个白痴
并注意，
for trident trouble comes.
因为三叉戟的麻烦来了。
- Sorry.
- Eh.
- 对不起。
- 呃。
all: See?
全体：看到了吗？
all chanting:
Food! Food! Food!
所有人都在喊口号：
食物！食物！食物！
Food! Food!
食物！食物！
- Food! Food!
- 食物！食物！
Oh.
哦。
- Hey, I was still
reading that!
- 嘿，我还在
读那个！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Forget the stupid comic.
- 忘记那些愚蠢的漫画吧。
We've got a situation here.
我们这里有情况。
We don't have
any Krabby Patties,
我们没有
任何蟹黄饼，
and these animals are trying
to eat us instead.
这些动物正在尝试
来吃我们。
[chomp]
[咀嚼]
Hey, who's responsible
for this?
哎，谁负责
为了这个？
- Get to flipping
those patties fast, boy-o!
- 开始翻转
这些肉饼快了，天啊！
Before we all become
the lunch special.
在我们都成为之前
特别午餐。
- I'm on it, Mr. Krabs.
- 我正在处理，蟹老板。
[bowling pins rattling]
[保龄球瓶嘎嘎作响]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
[straining]
[紧张]
Oh, the toppings
haven't been prepped.
哦，配料
还没有准备好。
I wish this lettuce and tomato
would just cut themselves up.
我希望这个生菜和西红柿
只会割伤自己。
- Let's do this!
- 让我们这样做吧！
- Yeah, cut me up good,
girlfriend.
- 是啊，把我切好，
女朋友。
[all grunting]
- Huh.
[全都咕哝]
- 嗯。
I guess I did cut up
the toppings after all.
我想我确实剪了
毕竟配料。
- 37 Krabby Patties!
- 37 个蟹肉饼！
Fast!
Ahhh!
快速地！
啊啊！
- 37 patties?
- 37块肉饼？
How am I gonna flip 37 patties?
我该如何翻转 37 个肉饼？
Huh, has my spatula
always had three heads?
嗯，有我的铲子
总是有三个头？
all: No!
全体：不！
And it is not a spatula.
而且它不是抹刀。
- Get them patties
out here fast, SpongeBob!
- 给他们买肉饼
快出来吧，海绵宝宝！
Ahh!
啊！
- Well, I wish
these Krabby Patties
- 嗯，我希望
这些蟹肉饼
would just serve themselves
so I could keep cooking.
只会为自己服务
这样我就可以继续做饭了。
[magical music]
[魔幻音乐]
- Hey!
- 嘿！
- Yay!
- 耶！
- Yeah!
- 是的！
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- Whoa, my spatula
never did that before.
- 哇哦，我的铲子
以前从未这样做过。
all: Krabby Patty!
Krabby Patty!
所有人：蟹蟹帕蒂！
蟹蟹帕蒂！
Krabby Patty!
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- [straining]
Huh?
- [紧张]
啊？
*
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
- Mmm.
- 嗯。
- Huh?
- 啊？
[laughing]
[笑]
I don't know how
you're doing this, boy-o,
我不知道怎么办
你正在这样做，男孩，
but keep it up.
但请坚持下去。
Folks will pay
every cent they have
人们会付出代价
他们拥有的每一分钱
to watch Krabby Patties dance.
观看蟹肉饼跳舞。
Look at how cute they are.
看看他们多可爱。
- Hey.
- Oh!
- 嘿。
- 哦！
- Whoo!
- Whoo-whee!
- 呼！
- 呼呼！
- We're running out
of them dancing patties.
- 我们快没了
他们跳舞的馅饼。
Faster, boy-o!
Faster!
快点，男孩！
快点！
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
Dance!
Come on, dance!
舞蹈！
来吧，跳舞吧！
I'm trying, Mr. Krabs.
I'm trying.
我正在努力，蟹老板。
我想。
Come on, you, work!
加油，你，工作吧！
- [grumbling]
- [抱怨]
all: The sponge has angered
the trident.
全体：海绵生气了
三叉戟。
Trouble comes.
麻烦来了。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- Ahh!
[angry grumbling]
- 啊！
[愤怒的抱怨]
- Ah.
- 啊。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- [snarling]
- [咆哮]
Ahh!
啊！
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- No!
- 不！
This is gonna
cost me money!
这将
花了我钱！
- Mr. Krabs, I wish
you wouldn't worry about money
- 蟹老板先生，我希望
你不会担心钱的问题
at a time like this.
在这样的时刻。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Right you are, boy-o.
你是对的，男孩。
Here, take this.
Here you go.
给，拿着这个。
干得好。
I can't stop!
我停不下来！
[both screaming]
[两人尖叫]
- There you go.
What's happening to me!
- 就这样吧。
我这是怎么了！
- What is going on
around here?
- 发生了什么事
这附近？
- Ahem.
- 咳咳。
- Hey, what's this?
- 嘿，这是什么？
Whoa!
哇！
My spatula is magic.
我的铲子有魔法。
all: Magic, magic, magic.
全部：魔法，魔法，魔法。
- This is awesome.
- 这太棒了。
I will use this magic spatula
to help everyone.
我会用这个神奇的抹刀
来帮助大家。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- I'll have two, please.
- 请给我两个。
- [crying]
- [哭泣]
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
[gasps]
I'll help you, baby!
[喘气]
我会帮助你的，宝贝！
Boing!
噗！
[whistles]
[口哨声]
- [crying]
- [哭泣]
- What's wrong, grass?
Why won't you grow?
-怎么了，草？
你为什么不成长？
Talk to me.
跟我说话。
Oh.
Mm.
哦。
毫米。
- We'll do more than just
talk to yous.
- 我们会做的不仅仅是
和你谈谈。
Let's see how you like
getting mowed.
让我们看看你喜欢什么
被割草。
- Ahhh!
- 啊啊！
- There is no problem
I cannot solve,
- 没有问题
我无法解决，
for I am SpongeBob,
Emperor of the Sea.
因为我是海绵宝宝，
海皇。
[triumphant music]
[胜利的音乐]
Hey, get outta here,
you pesky jellyfish!
嘿，离开这里，
你这个讨厌的水母！
all: Whoa, slow your roll.
所有人：哇哦，放慢你的速度。
Only Neptune,
true ruler of the sea,
只有海王星，
真正的海洋统治者，
can control the trident.
可以控制三叉戟。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- So I say, "Look, Zeus,
- 所以我说，“看，宙斯，
"either you come up
with more money
“要么你上来
有更多的钱
or Neptune walks."
或海王星行走。”
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
- There he is, ma.
- 他在那儿，妈妈。
That's the man who hit me.
就是那个打我的人。
[sobs]
[抽泣]
- Don't cry, baby.
- 别哭，宝贝。
Mother will handle this.
妈妈会处理这件事。
[snarls]
[咆哮]
- Let us battle!
- 让我们战斗吧！
Take that!
拿那个！
- Huh?
- 啊？
This is dry-clean only,
you monster!
这只能干洗，
你这个怪物！
- Ooh.
Huh?
- 哦。
啊？
"Property of SpongeBob"?
“海绵宝宝的财产”？
- [snarls]
- [咆哮]
- Uh-oh.
- 呃哦。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- Hey, SpongeBob.
- 嘿，海绵宝宝。
You look so sparkly today.
你今天看起来很闪闪发光。
- Of course I do,
for I am SpongeBob,
- 我当然知道，
因为我是海绵宝宝，
Emperor of the Sea.
海皇。
[triumphant music]
[胜利的音乐]
- Oh.
- 哦。
No!
My ice cream!
不！
我的冰淇淋！
Ohh, why is the world
so full of pain?
噢，世界为何如此
如此充满痛苦？
[sobs]
[抽泣]
- Fear not,
bestest of friends.
- 不要害怕，
最好的朋友。
You shall have all the ice cream
you could ever eat.
所有的冰淇淋都给你
你可以吃。
all: No, you'll only
make it worse.
全部：不，你只会
让情况变得更糟。
[upbeat jingle]
[欢快的顺口溜]
[music sputters, stops]
[音乐噼啪作响，停止]
- Ahhh!
Best day ever!
- 啊啊！
有史以来最好的一天！
- No, worst day ever.
- 不，这是有史以来最糟糕的一天。
Oh, my back.
哦，我的背。
all: See?
全体：看到了吗？
- I can fix this.
- 我可以解决这个问题。
- Hooray!
- 万岁！
- Boo!
- 嘘！
- I think I know a way
to make you both happy.
- 我想我知道一个办法
让你们俩都开心。
all: You really don't.
全体：你真的不知道。
How do you not
get that by now?
你怎么不
现在明白了吗？
- An ice cream geyser!
- 冰淇淋间歇泉！
Ahh!
啊！
Brain freeze!
大脑冻结！
I can't eat it all.
我不能全部吃完。
Ah, I've never been
more disappointed in myself.
啊，我从来没有去过
对自己更加失望。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- Ooh, I like choc--
- 哦，我喜欢巧克力--
- Oh, the creamy,
delicious horror.
- 哦，奶油味的，
美味的恐怖。
- Save us, SpongeBob!
- 拯救我们，海绵宝宝！
Save us!
救救我们吧！
No wait.
无需等待。
Okay, now save us!
好吧，现在拯救我们吧！
- Stop, ice cream!
Stop! Stop!
- 停下来，冰淇淋！
停止！停止！
- Hmm?
- 唔？
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
[both scream]
[两人尖叫]
- Oh, I just made it worse.
- 哦，我只是让事情变得更糟了。
Patrick,
I've ruined everything.
帕特里克，
我毁了一切。
- Oh, SpongeBob,
I wouldn't say that.
- 哦，海绵宝宝，
我不会这么说。
- Our baby!
- 我们的宝贝！
- I'll never mow you again!
- 我再也不会割你的了！
- Take me money!
- Ow!
- 给我钱！
- 噢！
Okay, SpongeBob,
you ruined everything.
好吧，海绵宝宝，
你毁了一切。
- No sponge should have
this much power.
- 海绵不应该有
这么大的力量。
all: We told you so.
全体：我们已经告诉过你了。
- Not helping.
- 没有帮助。
- Well, maybe I can help.
- 好吧，也许我能帮忙。
I believe I have
something of yours.
我相信我有
你的东西。
- My spatula!
- 我的铲子！
Then what's this?
那这是什么？
- That is my trident!
- 那是我的三叉戟！
- Well, take your trident.
I don't want it anymore.
- 好吧，带上你的三叉戟。
我不再想要了。
Whoa! Stop!
That wasn't me.
哇！停止！
那不是我。
all: Too long away
from its true master,
全体：距离太远了
来自它真正的主人，
the trident has run wild.
三叉戟已经狂奔。
- What a jerk.
- 真是个混蛋。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- Sorry.
Pardon me.
- 对不起。
对不起。
It stuck!
它卡住了！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- Ahh!
Make it stop!
- 啊！
让它停下来！
[triumphant music]
[胜利的音乐]
*
- You have been
one naughty trident.
- 你已经
一根淘气的三叉戟。
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
- Oh, I can't stay
mad at you.
- 哦，我不能留下来
生你的气。
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
- Now let's see if we can
fix all of this.
- 现在让我们看看是否可以
解决这一切。
- Give me back me money.
- 把钱还给我。
- [baby cooing]
- [婴儿咕咕声]
- Mow us good!
- 好好修剪我们吧！
- You know, SpongeBob,
your spatula is just as powerful
- 你知道，海绵宝宝，
你的抹刀同样强大
as my trident.
作为我的三叉戟。
- Really?
- 真的吗？
- Ha!
Not even close!
- 哈！
甚至还没有接近！
[laughs]
[笑]
But it's still pretty great.
但它仍然很棒。
- Thanks for bailing me out,
Neptune.
- 谢谢你救我出来
海王星。
If there's any way
I can ever help you,
如果有什么办法
我永远可以帮助你，
just let me know.
请告诉我。
- Well, there is one way.
- 嗯，有一种方法。
There they are!
他们在那里！
- [snarling]
- [咆哮]
[both gasp]
[两人都喘气]
- Let's get 'em!
- 让我们抓住他们！
[yelling]
[大喊]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]